Malden, Mass. First Church records, 1649-2016.
Congregational Library & Archives
- Publications, 1848 2013; 1848-2013
  - Programs, 1930 1949; 1930-1949 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Programs, 1932 1933; 1932-1933 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Programs, 1950 1957; 1950-1957 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Programs, 1958 1959; 1958-1959 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Programs, 1960 1961; 1960-1961 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Programs, 1962 1963; 1962-1963 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Programs, 1964 1965; 1964-1965 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Programs, 1966 1967; 1966-1967 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Programs, 1968 1969; 1968-1969 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Programs, 1970 1971; 1970-1971 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Programs, 1972 1973; 1972-1973 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Programs, 1974 1975; 1974-1975 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Programs, 1976 1977; 1976-1977 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Programs, 1978 1979; 1978-1979 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Programs, 1980 1981; 1980-1981 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Programs, 1982 1983; 1982-1983 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Programs, 1984 1985; 1984-1985 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Programs, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Programs, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Programs, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Programs, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Programs, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Programs, 1991 1992; 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Programs, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Programs, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Programs, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Programs, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Programs, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Programs, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Programs, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Programs, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Programs, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Programs, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Programs, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Programs, 2004 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Programs, 2005 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Programs, 2006 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Programs, 2007 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Programs, 2008 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Programs, 2009 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Programs, 2012 2013; 2012-2013 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Program and Information Brochures, 1918 2005; 1918-2005 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Published Histories, 1959 1978; 1959-1978 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Weekly Calendars, 1890 1898; 1890-1898 (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Related churches, 1774 1992; 1774-1992
  This series contains records from related churches that branched out of First Church in Malden and either rejoined upon closure or continued separately including Maplewood Congregational, Linden Congregational, Forestdale Community Church, Edgeworth Chapel, and First Congregational in Everett. The records include minutes, reports, histories, correspondence, guest books, sunday school records, member records, photos, record volumes, programs, and other documents.
  - Maplewood Congregational Church, 1772 1981; 1772-1981
    This subseries contains records from the Maplewood Congregational Church which formed from members of First Church in 1873 and rejoined First Church upon closure in 1978. The records contain minutes, programs, reports, guest books, member records, member cards, correspondence, record volumes, sunday school records, and other documents.
    - Chancel Revision Blueprint, undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Historical Documents, 1772 1876; 1772-1876 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Record Book No 1, 1874 1885; 1874-1885 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - First Congregational Society Minutes, 1874 1886; 1874-1886 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Member List, 1874 1891; 1874-1891 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Member Transfers, 1874 1896; 1874-1896 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Record Book No 3 and Register, 1874 1897; 1874-1897 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Record Book No 4 and Register, 1874 1912; 1874-1912 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Book of Remembrance Memorials and Minister List, 1874 1978; 1874-1978 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Index for Boof of Remembrance Memorials and Minister List, 1874 1978; 1874-1978 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Register, 1874 1978; 1874-1978 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Ecclesiastical Council Invitations and Delegate List, 1876 1896; 1876-1896 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Reports and Correspondence, 1876 1938; 1876-1938 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Property and Legal Records, 1876 1979; 1876-1979 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Maplewood News Notes, 1877 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Clerk Reports, 1877 1897; 1877-1897 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Sunday School Superintendent Reports, 1877 1905; 1877-1905 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - HIstories, 1879 1899; 1879-1899 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Sunday School Secretary Reports, 1879 1910; 1879-1910 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Early Records, Minutes, and Correspondence, 1881 1899; 1881-1899 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Sunday School Treasurer's Book, 1882 1924; 1882-1924 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Record Book No 2, 1885 1893; 1885-1893 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - First Congregational Society Minutes, 1886 1897; 1886-1897 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Rev. William Obear Memorial, 1894 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Member and Baptismal Cards, 1895 1957; 1895-1957 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous, 1896 1962; 1896-1962 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Standing Committee Minutes, 1897 1927; 1897-1927 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Collector Account Book, 1897 1941; 1897-1941 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Treasurer's Book, 1897 1943; 1897-1943 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Foreign Missionary Department Minutes, 1898 1911; 1898-1911 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Programs, 1900 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Programs, 1901 1908; 1901-1908 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Ladies Social Union Minutes, 1902 1912; 1902-1912 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Programs, 1903 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Conferences, 1905 1962; 1905-1962 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Sunday School Minutes and Class List, 1906 1917; 1906-1917 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Constitutions, 1910 1962; 1910-1962 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Church Meeting Minutes and Related Material, 1913 1938; 1913-1938 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Financial Records, 1919 1942; 1919-1942 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Programs, 1922 1969; 1922-1969 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Anniversaries, 1924 1969; 1924-1969 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Publicity, 1924 1978; 1924-1978 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Sunday School Treasurer's Book, 1925 1961; 1925-1961 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Standing Committee Minutes and Account Book, 1926 1953; 1926-1953 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Standing Committee Minutes, 1928 1936; 1928-1936 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Church Meeting Minutes and Related Material, 1939 1964; 1939-1964 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Collector's Account Ledger, 1942 1945; 1942-1945 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - 70th Anniversary, 1944 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Treasurer's Account Ledger, 1944 1946; 1944-1946 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Account Ledger, 1946 1957; 1946-1957 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Improvement and Anniversary Committee Minutes, 1954 1956; 1954-1956 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Annual Reports, 1954 1975; 1954-1975 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Wills and Bequests, 1955 1970; 1955-1970 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Sexton Estate Records, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Parish and Member Lists, 1956 1959; 1956-1959 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Church Improvement, 1956 1961; 1956-1961 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Church Committee Minutes, 1957 1959; 1957-1959 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Guest Book, 1957 1962; 1957-1962 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Church Committee Minutes and Newstories, 1957 1968; 1957-1968 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Standing Committee Minutes and Correspondence, 1959 1978; 1959-1978 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Guest Book, 1960 1962; 1960-1962 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Member Transfers and Removals, 1960 1971; 1960-1971 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Guest Book, 1962 1970; 1962-1970 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Church Committee Minutes and Correspondence, 1968 1974; 1968-1974 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Guest Book, 1968 1978; 1968-1978 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Sunday School Attendence, 1968 1978; 1968-1978 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Children's Day Programs, 1972 1978; 1972-1978 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Standing Committee Meeting Notes, 1973 1978; 1973-1978 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Church Committee Minutes, Reports, and Correspondence, 1973 1979; 1973-1979 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - 100th Anniversary, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence and Mailing List, 1978 1981; 1978-1981 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Donation List and Thank You Letters, 1979 1980; 1979-1980 (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Organ Transfer Letters and Programs, 1979 1980; 1979-1980 (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - Second Church Minutes and Member List, 1744 1788; 1744-1788 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Copy of Second Church Minutes and Member List and Related Letters, 1744 1788; 1744-1788 (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - Everett Establishment, 1848 (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - Record Extracts about Edgeworth Missionary Society, 1852 1890; 1852-1890 (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - Linden Miscellaneous, 1888 1971; 1888-1971 (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - Linden Photos, 1951 1979; 1951-1979 (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - Forestdale Correspondence and Records, 1927 1992; 1927-1992 (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - "An Historical Sketch of Forestdale Chapel...", 1968 (Box 16, Folder 34)
- Audiovisual material, 1649 2001; 1649-2001
  This series contains audiovisual materials including VHS, CDs, floppy disks, photographs, photo slides, glass slides, cassette tapes, video 8 tapes, vinyl records, photo albums, drawings, images from publications, polaroids, and microfilm.
  - Banner Heading, undated (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Blomerth (Column Building) Photos, undated (Box 16, Folder 35)
  - Colonial Pulpit Glass Slide, undated (Box 19, Item 29)
  - Congo Dinner, undated (Box 16, Folder 36)
  - Drawings of Church Building, undated (Box 16, Folder 37)
  - Floppy Disks 1-10, undated (Box 19, Item 1-10)
  - Glass Slides 1-12, undated (Box 19, Item 17-28)
  - Irving Street Church Negative, undated (Box 16, Folder 38)
  - Manners Photo Guide, undated (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Members on Front Steps, undated (Box 16, Folder 39)
  - Member Photos, undated (Box 16, Folder 40)
  - Miscellaneous Photos, undated (Box 16, Folder 41)
  - Miscellaneous Photos, undated (Box 16, Folder 42)
  - Miscellaneous Photos, undated (Box 16, Folder 43)
  - Performance Photos, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Polaroids, undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Repair Photos, undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Sarah's Baby Shower, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Service Cassette Tape, undated (Box 18, Item 1-93)
  - Show and Cast Photos, undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Souvenir of Malden Photo Book, undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Video 8 Tape 1, undated (Box 19, Item 14)
  - Video 8 Tape 2, undated (Box 19, Item 15)
  - Video 8 Tape 3, undated (Box 19, Item 16)
  - White Gift Service, undated (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Youth Trip Tape 1, undated (Box 19, Item 13)
  - Images from Publications and Historical Displays, 1649 1949; 1649-1949 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Microfilm reel 1, 1770 1959; 1770-1887, 1959 (Box 24)
    Contents of Reel
    Church records, 1770-1887; Trinitarian Society records, 1832-1850; Church history covering 1649-1959 by Ruth K. Randall, 1959
  - Reverend Portaits, 1770 1978; 1770-1978 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Church Building Photos, 1867 1933; 1867-1933 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Microfilm reel 2, 1887 1972; 1887-1972 (Box 25)
    Church records volume 4, 1887-1905; Church records volume 5, 1905-1927; Church records volume 6, 1928-1941; Church records volume 7, 1941-1972
  - Sunday School Picnic, 1895 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Malden 250th Celebration, 1899 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Christmas Party Photo, 1908 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Ambulance Photo, 1917 (Box 17, Folder 51)
  - Miscellaneous Photos, 1917 2001; 1917-2001 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Groups and Activities, 1920 1929; circa 1920s (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Beacon Class, 1933 1935; 1933-1935 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Church Photo Album, 1933 1955; 1933-1955 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Building and Event Photo Compilations, 1933 1977; 1933-1977 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous Photos, 1941 1955; 1941-1955 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Kindergarten Photos, 1943 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Tercentenary Pageant Alton Woods Collection, 1949 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Tercentenary Year Photos, 1949 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Historical Photos, 1949 1982; 1949-1982 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Holiday Services, 1949 1982; 1949-1982 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Rev. Minich 25th Anniversary, 1951 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Church Picnic, 1952 1955; 1952-1955 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Church Events Photo Slides, 1952 1975; 1952-1975 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Trip Pictures, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Miscellaneous Photos, 1956 1975; 1956-1975 (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Dr. Minich's Going Away Party and 7:30 Club Reunion, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - Mother's Club Photo Album, 1957 1964; 1957-1964 (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - Church School Slides, 1959 1975; 1959-1975 (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - Microfilm reel 3, 1959 1977; 1959-1977 (Box 26)
    First church history sequel, 1959-1971; Epiloque to history sequel, 1971-1975; 325th Anniversary booklet, 1974; Records, 1972-1976; Records annual meeting, 1977
  - Photo Slides, 1960 1987; 1960-1987 (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - Music of First Church in Malden Record, 1963 (Box 22, Folder 2-3)
  - Photos from Slides, 1967 1987; 1967-1987 (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - Miscellaneous Photos, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 32)
  - Directory Photos, 1960 1969; circa 1960s (Box 17, Folder 33)
  - Winter Trip, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 34)
  - Oration Sunday Photo Booklet, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 35)
  - Photos for Church Symbols Display, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 36)
  - Confirmation Class, 1978 1981; 1978-1981 (Box 17, Folder 37)
  - Miscellaneous Photos, 1978 1999; 1978-1999 (Box 17, Folder 38)
  - Service Photos, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 39)
  - Church Honoring Members, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 40)
  - Church Honoring Members, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 41)
  - Member Photos, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 42)
  - Church School Photo Album, 1988 1992; 1988-1992 (Box 17, Folder 43)
  - Tea, 1980 1989; circa 1980s (Box 17, Folder 44)
  - Helen C's Pictures (Basketball), 1990 (Box 17, Folder 45)
  - Rev. Randy Ferrara's 25th Ordination Anniversary Dinner, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 46)
  - Miscellaneous Photos, 1998 (Box 17, Folder 47)
  - 350th Anniversary VHS, 1999 (Box 19, Item 30-31)
  - Dinner Photos, 1999 (Box 17, Folder 48)
  - Malden 350th Anniversary Parade, 1999 (Box 17, Folder 49)
  - Rev. Charlene Johnson's Computer Files, 1999 2001; 1999-2001 (Box 19, Item 12)
  - Christmas Pageant Photos Taken by Qin Zia, 2001 (Box 17, Folder 50)
  - First Church Chancel Choir Bay State Bach Ensemble, 2003 (Box 19, Item 11)